# Senaka Suriyaarachchi

# Senior Java Developer / Technical Project Manager

- O Colombo, Sri Lanka
- **\** +94714572747
- @ senaka@hotmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/senakas

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Software Developer, who has experience in Java (including Spring, Micronaut, JHipster, Apache Scout and Vaadin), JavaScript (including Angular, Ionic Framework), .NET C#, SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, Perl. I have handson experience in Oracle, Informix, MSSQL and MySQL databases as a developer as well as DBA.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

May 2018-Current

### Senior Java Developer / Technical Project Manager

- Care Systems Inc
- Sri Lanka

Convert Swing based Java solution to Web Enable by using Core Java,

Java Servlet, JSP, Core Java Scripts.

Enable Data visualization capabilities using Apache Superset and Apache ECharts.

Develop Job Bank application using Angular, Java Script, Oracle Apex and Oracle,

January 2017-April 2018

## Senior Developer / Delivery Unit

- **E** Eyepax IT Consulting Private Limited
- Colombo, Sri Lanka

Develop a e-commerce application using .NET C#, MSSQL and nopcommerce e-commerce platform.

May 2013-December 2016

### Senior Developer / Technical PM

- Seneru Information Technologies
- O Colombo, Sri Lanka

Develop a Logistics Management System using .NET C# and MSSQL,

September 2008-April 2013

### Senior Developer / Divisional Manager

- BellVantage Pvt Ltd
- O Colombo, Sri Lanka

Developed an Insurance Management System using .NET C# and MSSQL, Developed CRM Module for Telecom Billing System using Java and Oracle.

May 2003-August 2008

#### Senior Developer / Technical PM

- eBuilder Technology Center
- O Colombo, Sri Lanka

Developed a Supply Chain Management System using Java, Java Spring and Oracle,

January 2000-April 2003

# Java Developer / Technical PM

- LogicalTech Cooperation
- Colombo, Sri Lanka

Developed an e-Commerce Solution using Java, EJB and Oracle,

July 1999-January 2000

# Java Developer

- Mobinetix (Pvt) Ltd
- Colombo, Sri Lanka

Convert Digital Receipt Management System from client-server to webcentric system using JSP, Servlet, core Java Script and Oracle.

January 1997-June 1999

### **Developer / Informix DBA**

- Mobitel (Pvt) Ltd
- O Colombo, Sri Lanka

Develop the telecom billing system using Informix 4GL, Java and Informix

DB. Responsibilities as DBA include database migration from Informix SE to Informix Online Dynamic Server 7.21, Insurance

# **EDUCATION**

1992-1996

### B. Sc.

- University of Colombo
- O Colombo, Sri Lanka

University of Colombo - Sri Lanka (1992-1996)

B. Sc. Computer Science

Computer Science

# **SKILLS**

JAVA Oracle PL/SQL Eclipse EJB JSP Servlet Spring .NET C# Ionic Javascript
MS .NET .Net Core PERL Python Vaadin Database Informix Mysql SQL APEX
Data Visualization Apache PMP Client-Server Telco Billing CRM Visualization Logistics
Logistics Management Supply Chain Supply Chain Management Certified PMP Telecom
Insurance Management Project Management Invoicing Telecom Billing Customer Relationship Management
Micronout

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Certified PMP** 

PMP

# **LANGUAGES**

English - Intermediate